<?xml version='1.0'?>

<project>
        <name>People2D: realtime people detection in 2D range data</name>

        <author>
		<name>Luciano Spinello</name>
		<url>http://www.informatik.uni-freiburg.de/~spinello</url>
	</author>

        <briefdescription>
	People2D provides an efficient implementation of the people detector in 2D data originally 
	developed in Human Detection using Multimodal and Multidimensional Features (ICRA 2008). 
	It includes training and detection module C++ source code and example files. 
	The code has been written in a way that it is very easy to modify / hack. 
	NO background subtraction is needed with this method. 
	The detector runs at 2KHz on a fast computer (i7 CPU - 1.6Ghz) 
        </briefdescription>

        <description>
        People2D is a principled approach for detecting people in 2D range data.
        It is based on discriminative classification of 
        a rich geometrical/statistical feature-set for describing  people in 2D range data.
		The method first segments 2D range data via jump-distance clustering, computes descriptors,
		and runs Adaboost prediction. The approach allows detections in single frames, without the need of 
		tracking and background-learning. It can been used in indoor, outdoor, from a static or a moving platform. 
		Appropriate training data must be provided to the algorithm to perform well in all cases.
		For showing the functionalities of the software, an uncluttered indoor toy data set 
		containing training / testing files is provided. 
		Tools for visualization, quantitative performance evaluation 
		(precision-recall curves) are also included in the package.
		It is considered state-of-the-art in the field of 2D detection from single frames (03/2011).
        </description>

        <requirement>
	Developed under Linux (GCC). Tested under Linux. Requires GSL.
	</requirement>

	<input>
	Logfile of 2D range data
	</input>

	<logformat> 
	
	The file format used is very simple. A single text file contains a set of 2D laser scans in which each line represents a single scan.
	ID1 X11 Y11 L11 X12 Y12 L12 ... X1N Y1N L1N
	ID2 X2 Y21 L21 X22 Y22 L22 ... X2N Y2N L2N
	
	ID is the numeric identifier of the scan (ignored), Xp and Yp are the cartesian coordinates of the point p, Lp is the binary 
	label of point p (0 if people -- 1 if background). The value of Lp is ignored when the file is read for people detection.
	</logformat>


	<paper>
		<title>Human Detection using Multimodal and Multidimensional Features.</title>
		<authorlist>L.Spinello, R.Siegwart</authorlist>
			<publishedin>IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)</publishedin>
				<year>2008</year>
				<url>http://www.informatik.uni-freiburg.de/~spinello/spinello08human.pdf</url>
		<title>Using Boosted Features for the Detection of People in 2D Range Data.</title>
		<authorlist>Arras K.O., Mozos O.M., Burgard W</authorlist>
			<publishedin>IEEE International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)</publishedin>
				<year>2007</year>
				<url>http://www.informatik.uni-freiburg.de/~arras/papers/arrasICRA07.pdf</url>
	</paper>

	<license>People2D is licenced under Creative Commons BY-NC-SA 3.0</license>

	<furthermore>
	C++ code, well-coded, compact, efficient.
	</furthermore>

</project>
